Richard D'Lonesteen

City rd,
London
EC1Y 2AG
07564059192
Richardlonesteen@gmail.com
www.undersky.co.uk/home

Summary

After University I had a unique opportunity to do something adventurous. So I and eventually another person started working on a project that we called Undersky.co.uk. It was an exciting journey during which I have learned a lot about starting a business. From doing the research and writing a business plan to doing presentation in competitions and in front of potential investors.

But most importantly I fell in love with **Ruby-on-Rails** and the whole development process. Prior to this project I didn't really have much web development experience apart from some small projects in college with **ASP.net** and **php**. And in university we were concentrating on **C++**, **C#**, **JAVA** and various design platforms. Over the duration of Undersky project I have learned quite a lot about **RoR**, **CSS** (**bootstrap**), **JavaScript**, **jQuery** and **SQL**. It was a tough journey, learning everything from scratch on my own while working on it. Due to this journey I really feel confident enough to join a team and actively contribute to new projects.

Education

2009-2012 – Staffordshire University, **BSc. Computer game design and programming (2.1)** 2007-2009 – Worcester College of Technology, **Software Development (DDM)**

Work experience

2013-2014 - Undersky.co.uk, Start-up Co-founder and developer

Undersky was an idea based on belief that our neighbourhoods can be friendlier, safer and more sociable for everyone. Thus we wanted to create a private social network for neighbours that would include hire and rental market of underutilized items, and a skill-sharing platform. Most of the time there were only two of us working on it. I was responsible for the **research**, **planning**, **designing** and **programming** of the platform.

2013-2014 - St. Davids Hotel, restaurant assistant

This was an easy and relaxing part-time social job that kept me afloat while I was working on the start-up.

Core software skills

Ruby-on-Rails – Rspec -CSS – JavaScript – SQL - jQuery Bootstrap – HTML – SQL - Adobe Photoshop – Adobe Fireworks – Adobe Illustrator